Finding Aid for James J. Duderstadt Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Digital Documents
  - Faculty Archives, 1968-ongoing; 1312 digital files
    - A Proposal to the NSF for a Small Grant for Exploratory Research (SGER) to Develop a Undergraduate Minor Concentration in Nuclear Fission Power Engineering, 2001
    - Prospectus of Millennium Project, 2001
    - Reponses of JJD to follow-up questions from the Committee on Science, Subcommittee on Energy and Environment, 2001
    - Response to questions relating to proposal to develop a transportable model of summer institute, 2001
    - Sigma Xi Forum Notes, 2001
    - Strawman Document for Workshop, 2001
    - Preparing Future Faculty for Future Universities, 1/12/2001
    - Internet2 Statute, 2/6/2001
    - First guns, then pills--next big research investment will be in brainpowers, says U-M professors, 2/18/2001
    - Science Policy for the Next 50 Years - From Guns to Pills to Brains…, 2/18/2001
    - Science Policy for the Next 50 Years - From Guns to Pills to Brains… (1.0), 2/18/2001
    - Science Policy for the Next 50 Years - From Guns to Pills to Brains… (2), 2/18/2001
    - The Importance of Liberal Learning for an Increasingly Technological World, 3/15/2001
    - From Guns to Pills to Brains: Shifting Federal Research Priorities for the 21st Century, 4/10/2001
    - The Future of the University in the Digital Age, 4/22/2001
    - The Future of the University in the Digital Age, 5/31/2001
    - The Future of the University in the Digital Age, 5/31/2001
    - Preparing for the Revolution: The Future of the University in the Digital Age, 5/31/2001
    - The Challenges and Hazards of Leading The University Transformations Demanded by a Learning Society, 6/11/2001
    - Leading Higher Education In an Era of Rapid Change, 7/30/2001
    - Leading Higher Education In an Era of Rapid Change, 7/30/2001
    - A Pre-proposal for a Planning Grant, 8/6/2001
    - Some Observations on the Current State And the Future of Intercollegiate Athletics (3), 10/18/2001
    - In Search of a 2x4: Change and the Academy, 10/19/2001
    - In Search of a 2x4: Change and the Academy (1.2), 10/19/2001
    - In Search of a 2x4: Change and the Academy, 11/7/2001
    - Leading Higher Education In an Era of Rapid Change, 11/16/2001
    - Leading Higher Education In an Era of Rapid Change (1.0), 11/16/2001
    - The Future of the University in the Digital Age, 12/4/2001
    - AAU Colloquium, 2002
    - APS MilProj Project ("21st Century Educational Needs Project"), 2002
    - ASEE Keynotes: The Urgency of Engineering Education Reform, 2002
    - The Development on a Undergraduate Minor Concentration in Nuclear Fission Power Engineering, 2002
    - A Free Lunch for the North Campus Deans, 2002
    - In the beginning…there was the central 40 acre campus (1), 2002
    - In the beginning…there was the central 40 acre campus (2), 2002
    - Information Technology and the Future of the Research University (NRC), 2002
    - Information Technology and the Future of the University, 2002
    - Information Technology and the Future of the University (5.0), 2002
    - The Interaction between Public and Private Higher Education, 2002
    - Intercollegiate athletics, 2002
    - Letter of congratulations to Mary Sue Coleman, 2002
    - Letter to Werner Hirsch regarding ideas of the Glion IV conference, 2002
    - The Michigan-Oberlin-Kalamazoo Project, A Partnership between Liberal Arcs Colleges and Research Universities, 2002
    - NAS/NAE/IOM/NRC Study - The Impact of Information Technology on the Future of the Research University, 2002
    - The Nuclear Energy Research Advisory Committee (NERAC) of the Dept. of Energy, and the Future of the DOE's Nuclear Energy Research Programs, 2002
    - Preparing for the Revolution, Information Technology and the Future of the Research University, 2002
    - A Proposal to Establish a Michigan Higher Education Policy Institute, 2002
    - Regarding a three-year grant from Atlantic Philanthropics, 2002
    - To: Members of the Original "dream team" for the Media Union, 2002
    - The UM College of Engineering, 2002
    - The Ultimate Intelligent Platform: The American Research University, 2002
    - Views from the Media Union Pioneers, 2002
    - Year, roles, activity, methods, and tools of JJD's academic life, 2002
    - Preparing for the Revolution - Information Technology and the Future of the Research University, 1/23/2002
    - Darwinian Medicine for the University, 4/4/2002
    - Commercialization of the Academy: Seeking a Balance between the Marketplace and Public Interest - Emory, 4/6/2002
    - Commercialization of the Academy: Seeking a Balance between the Marketplace and Public Interest - Emory, 4/6/2002
    - Project Report of the Atlantic Philanthropies - Education in the Digital Age: Leadership, Linkages, and Roadmaps, 4/15/2002
    - Diversity and Equity in College Sports: The Need for Change, 5/21/2002
    - Diversity and Equity in College Sports: The Need for Change - MSU, 5/21/2002
    - Higher Education in the New Century, 6/22/2002
    - Higher Education in the New Century: Themes, Challenges, and Opportunities, 6/22/2002
    - Taxonomy for MilProj - DRAFT 1, 6/27/2002
    - The University of Michigan Media Union Reunion - Dreams of the Past; Challenges of the Present; Opportunities of the Future, 8/11/2002
    - Comments a John Seely Brown Symposium, 10/4/2002
    - Speculating about the Future of the University of the 21st Century…for a 21st Century University, 10/18/2002
    - Speculating about the Future of the University of the 21st Century…for a 21st Century University (2.0), 10/18/2002
    - Regarding a three-year grant from Atlantic Philanthropics, 10/24/2002
    - A Tour of the "I Culture": Digital Gadgets and Gizmos, 10/25/2002
    - The Future of Higher Education in the Knowledge-Driven, Global Economy of the 21st Century, 10/31/2002
    - The Future of Higher Education in the Knowledge-Driven, Global Economy of the 21st Century (1.2), 10/31/2002
    - The Future of Higher Education in the Knowledge-Driven, Global Economy of the 21st Century (1.4), 10/31/2002
    - The Future of Higher Education in the Knowledge-Driven, Global Economy of the 21st Century (2), 10/31/2002
    - The Future of Higher Education in the Knowledge-Driven, Global Economy of the 21st Century (redline), 10/31/2002
    - Governing the 21st Century University: A View from the Bridge (2.0), 11/21/2002
    - Governing the 21st Century University: A View from the Bridge, 11/23/2002
    - Governing the 21st Century University: A View from the Bridge (2.1), 11/23/2002
    - Letter to Werner Hirsch regarding ideas of the Glion IV conference, 12/3/2002
    - Assisting Universities in Developing Cyberinfrastructure Strategies for Research and Education, 2003
    - The Changing Nature of Research and the Future of the Research University - Powerpoint, 2003
    - College Sports, 2003
    - Engineering Education at Michigan - Past, Present, and Future, 2003
    - The Evolution of Information Technology, 2003
    - Federal Science and Technology, 2003
    - The Future - Engineering Education for the 21st Century, 2003
    - The George H.W. Bush "Lifetime of Leadership" Awards, Acceptance remarks, 2003
    - Gratz et al v Bollinger et al., 2003
    - Information Technology and the Future of the University, 2003
    - Introduction, 2003
    - Key Points related to the Ford Nuclear Reactor at the Phoenix Memorial Laboratory, 2003
    - Letter to the Michigan Daily clarifying remarks on "Duderstadt criticizes current diversity plan", 2003
    - Michigan Engineering History, 2003
    - Missouri Address 1.0, 2003
    - Nuclear Science and Energy R&D - A Strategy for the Nation, 2003
    - On the Move, a Personal History of Michigan's College of Engineering in Modern Times, 2003
    - The Past, 2003
    - A Photographic History of UM Engineering, 2003
    - Preface for Glion IV, 2003
    - The Present - and a bit of "personal" history, 2003
    - Rebooting the U.S. Civilian Nuclear Power Program, 2003
    - Regional Learning Ecologies - A Technology Roadmapping Exercise, 2003
    - Reinventing the Research University: An American perspective, 2003
    - Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities, and Threats (SWOT) Analysis for The Office of Science of the Department on Energy (DOE-SC), 2003
    - Technological Singularities, 2003
    - UNC Chapel Hill Discussion, 2003
    - University of Michigan Photographic Saga, 2003
    - The Use of Undergraduate Minors to Meet National Need in Nuclear Fission Power Engineering, 2003
    - A Pre-Proposal - Summer Faculty Careers Institute for Ph.D. students, Postdoctoral Fellows, and Junior Faculty, 1/14/2003
    - A Pre-Proposal - Summer Faculty Careers Institute for Ph.D. students, Postdoctoral Fellows, and Junior Faculty, 1/17/2003
    - Task Force on the Future of Science Programs at the Department of Energy, 1/22/2003
    - Higher Education in the New Century: Themes, Challenges, and Options (UCLA), 2/6/2003
    - Higher Education in the New Century: Themes, Challenges, and Options (USC), 2/6/2003
    - An Epilogue to the Paperback Edition of Intercollegiate Athletics and the American University: A University President's Perspective, 2003-03
    - An Epilogue to the Paperback Edition of Intercollegiate Athletics and the American University: A University President's Perspective (2), 2003-03
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World (Missouri), 3/5/2003
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World (Missouri NE), 3/6/2003
    - Memo to Washington and Richardson, subject: Federal Science and Technology Budget, 3/28/2003
    - Addendum - Project Report to the Atlantic Philanthropies, Education in the Digital Age: Leadership, Linkages, and Roadmaps, 4/15/2003
    - Project Report to the Atlantic Philanthropies, Education in the Digital Age: Leadership, Linkages, and Roadmaps, 4/15/2003
    - A NAS-NAE-IOE GUIRR Study, 4/17/2003
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World (Ohio State), 5/15/2003
    - STPP Task Team Report, 5/30/2003
    - The Changing Nature of Research and the Future of the Research University - Glion IV, 6/22/2003
    - Reinventing the Research University: An American perspective (Canadian Provosts), 6/22/2003
    - Reinventing the Research University: An American perspective (Glion), 6/22/2003
    - Memo to participants in Summit on "Transforming Research Universities Through Information Technology", regarding possible areas for follow up, 6/27/2003
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World, 7/22/2003
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World, 7/22/2003
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World (Miami), 7/22/2003
    - Memo to Coleman, naming of the Media Union, 9/19/2003
    - The Changing Nature of Research and the Future of the Research University, 10/1/2003
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World, 10/1/2003
    - The Changing Nature of Research and the Future of the Research University - Texas, 10/7/2003
    - The Future of the American Research University, 10/7/2003
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World, 10/7/2003
    - Critical Choices: Science, Energy, and Security, 10/13/2003
    - Critical Choices: Science, Energy, and Security, 10/13/2003
    - Project Report to the Atlantic Philanthropies, Education in the Digital Age: Leadership, Linkages, and Roadmaps, 10/15/2003
    - Some Notes of NSF "Tutorial" on Technology and Learning, 10/29/2003
    - The Impact of Information Technology on the Future of the Research University - An Update on a National Academies Study, 11/16/2003
    - The George H.W. Bush "Lifetime of Leadership" Awards, Acceptance remarks, 11/21/2003
    - Age of knowledge, 2004
    - A Case Study: France, 2004
    - Cyberinfrastructure and the future of the World Research University, 2004
    - Ford School briefing on STPP Task Force, 2004
    - Future - Over the Horizon, 2004
    - The Future of Nuclear Power, 2004
    - The Future…the Near Term, 2004
    - Higher Learning in the Digital Age, 2004
    - Hydrogen Initiatives Draft 2.2, 2004
    - Innovation Theme, 2004
    - Introduction, 2004
    - Keynote Address, James Duderstadt, U of M, 2004
    - Memo to Ulaby, related to MMPP, 2004
    - Memo to Ulaby, related to umich alternative energy, 2004
    - NAS/NAE/IOM/NRC Study - The Impact of Information Technologies on the Future of the Research University, 2004
    - The New Engineering - Challenges for the 21st Century, 2004
    - The North Woods Master Plan, 2004
    - Phase Two: The IT Forum, 2004
    - A Proposal to Assess the Capacity of the U.S. Engineering Research Enterprised to Meet the Future Needs of the Nation, 2004
    - Rebalancing the Federal R&D Enterprise, 2004
    - Redefining the Engineering Profession and Reinventing Engineering Education for a 21st Century Global Knowledge-driven Society, 2004
    - Regents Information Item (MMPP), 2004
    - Regional Learning Ecologies - A Technology Roadmapping Exercise, 2004
    - Reinventing the University Glion IV, 2004
    - STPP Next Steps, 2004
    - Some Thoughts about Your Future as a Michigan Engineering Student, 2004
    - Space Application, 2004
    - U. of Florida, President Machen inauguration, 2004
    - UC Santa Cruz Precatory Review, 2004
    - Report of the WASC Visiting Team, Preparatory Review, 2/4/2004
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World, 2/16/2004
    - Basic Research and the U.S. Energy Challenge - Fully Engaging U.S. Universities, 3/5/2004
    - Rationale for Recommendation, regarding UCSC, 3/5/2004
    - Diversity in Higher Education, 3/17/2004
    - Ethics and Values in the Contemporary University, 3/27/2004
    - Diversity in the Science and Engineering Community: Life after the Michigan Cases, 3/28/2004
    - Project Report to the Atlantic Philanthropics - Education in the Digital Age: Leadership, Linkages, and Roadmaps, 2004-04
    - Higher Learning in the Digital Age: An Update on a National Academies Study, 5/21/2004
    - Navigating through the Stormy Seas of a Changing World, 6/15/2004
    - The Committee to Assess the Capacity of The U.S. Engineering Research Enterprise, 6/16/2004
    - UNC-Chapel Hill Briefing, 7/20/2004
    - Global Climate Change, 8/13/2004
    - Fixing the Fragmented University: A View from the Bridge, 2004-09
    - Higher Learning in the Digital Age: An Update on a National Academies Study, 10/20/2004
    - Higher Learning in the Digital Age: An Update on a National Academies Study (Educause), 10/20/2004
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Hydrogen Initiatives - Prelim. Report, 2005
    - Assisting Universities in Developing Cyberinfrastructure Strategies for Research and Education, 2005
    - Concerns, 2005
    - The Crisis in Financing Public Higher Education - and a Possible Solution: A 21st C Learn Grant Act, 2005
    - The Crisis in Financing Public Higher Education - and a Possible Solution: A 21st C Learn Grant Act (2), 2005
    - Engineering Research and America's Future - Meeting the Challenges of a Global Economy, 2005
    - The Evolution of Information Technology, 2005
    - Higher Education in the New Century: Themes, Challenges, and Opportunities, 2005
    - The IT Forum: Preparing for the Revolution Redux, 2005
    - The IT Forum: Preparing for the Revolution Redux (Summary), 2005
    - Information Technology and the Future of the University, 2005
    - Introduction, 2005
    - A New Program in Science, Technology, and Public Policy, 2005
    - Positioning the United States for a Global Knowledge Economy, 2005
    - Regents Naming, 2005
    - A Roadmap to Michigan's Future, 2005
    - A Roadmap to Michigan's Future (2), 2005
    - Rotary sports speech, 2005
    - Santa Cruz Remarks, 2005
    - Some Thoughts on Framing the Work on the Commission and the National Dialog (1), 2005
    - Some Thoughts on Framing the Work on the Commission and the National Dialog (2), 2005
    - Thanks for the naming of the Duderstadt Center, 2005
    - Time to Get it Right - A Strategy for Higher Education in Kansas City, 2005
    - Universities and Business Glion V, 2005
    - Universities of the World and in the World, 2005
    - The Future of the University: A Perspective from the Oort Cloud, 3/8/2005
    - Fixing the Fragmented University: A View from the Bridge, 2005-09
    - A Roadmap to Michigan's Future: Meeting the Challenge of a Global Knowledge-Driven Economy, 2005-09
    - The Privately Financed Public University: A Case Study of the University of Michigan-Ann Arbor, 11/1/2005
    - The Great Lakes Region and the Knowledge Economy - A Roadmap to the Future (Fireside Chat), 11/2/2005
    - The Great Lakes Region and the Knowledge Economy, A Roadmap to the Future (Fed. Reserve Chicago), 11/2/2005
    - Briefing: Great Lakes Regional Economic Initiative, 11/3/2005
    - Diversity in the Science and Engineering Before and After Michigan Cases: Do We Need a New Paradigm?, 11/15/2005
    - 21st Century Engineering, 2006
    - 21st Century Engineering: A Roadmap to the Future, 2006
    - AGB Task Force on University Presidency, 2006
    - The American University - Challenges for the 21st Century, 2006
    - Energy Research at the University of Michigan - A commitment to Michigan's Future, 2006
    - Engineering Research and America's Future: Meeting the Challenges of a Global Economy, 2006
    - Federal R&D Policy, 2006
    - A Federal-State Compact to Review the Great Lakes Region, 2006
    - Future - Over the Horizon, 2006
    - The Future of Higher Education in the United States, 2006
    - The Future…The Near Term, 2006
    - Institutional Saga, 2006
    - JJD Remarks, 2006
    - Learn Grant, 2006
    - The Michigan Saga, 2006
    - Moral Leadership, 2006
    - NAS/NAE/IOM/NRC Study - The Impact of Information Technology on the Future of the Research University, 2006
    - Some Informal Notes on Compensation Programs for Faculty and Senior Academic Leadership, 2006
    - Some Observations on the SOE's Task Force on Higher Ed, 2006
    - Some Thoughts on Framing the Work of the Commission and the National Dialog, 2006
    - Universal Access to Lifelong Learning, 2006
    - The University of Michigan, 2006
    - University of Michigan Energy Research - Yesterday, Today, and Tomorrow, 2006
    - A Status Report from the Quality Subcommittee National Commission on the Future of Higher Education, 2/2/2006
    - Working Draft of the Quality Subcommittee of the Secretary of Education's Commission on the Future of Higher Education, 3/14/2006
    - Working Draft of the Quality Subcommittee of the Secretary of Education's Commission on the Future of Higher Education (Report), 3/14/2006
    - Task Force on UC Compensation, Accountability, and Transparency, 2006-04
    - A Proposal for Establishing The Phoenix Memorial Energy Institute of the University of Michigan, 6/1/2006
    - A Proposal for Establishing The Phoenix Memorial Energy Institute of the University of Michigan (Poster), 6/1/2006
    - A Test of Leadership: charting the future of U.S. Higher education, 8/9/2006
    - A Test of Leadership - Charting the Future of U.S. Higher Education, 2006-09
    - The Leadership Imperative (1), 9/20/2006
    - The Leadership Imperative (3), 9/20/2006
    - The Leadership Imperative, 9/25/2006
    - The Report of the AGB Task Force on the State of the Presidency in American Higher Education, 9/25/2006
    - Remarks on the Anniversary of the Merit Computer Network, 11/16/2006
    - Written Testimony of JJD to the Senate Finance Committee, 12/5/2006
    - 21st Century Engineering, 2007
    - The Crisis in Financing Public Higher Education - and a Possible Solution: A 21st C Learn Grant Act, 2007
    - The Energy Wars: Some Lessons Learned, 2007
    - Engineering Research and America's Future: Meeting the Challenges of a Global Economy, 2007
    - Engineering for a Changing Road, A Roadmap to the Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education, 2007
    - Executive Summary, 2007
    - Globalization of the University, 2007
    - Higher Education in the 21st Century - Global Imperatives, Regional Challenges, National Responsibilities, and Emerging Opportunities, 2007
    - Higher Education in the 21st Century - National Imperatives, Global Opportunities, 2007
    - Higher Education in the United States, 2007
    - How Do We Get From Here to There?, 2007
    - A New Program in Science, Technology, and Public Policy, 2007
    - Paradigm Shifts (Glion), 2007
    - Paradigm Shifts (Salzburg), 2007
    - Positioning the United States for a Global Knowledge Economy, 2007
    - A Roadmap to 21st Century Engineering, 2007
    - A Roadmap to Michigan's Future (Presentation), 2007
    - Some Informal Notes on Compensation Programs for Faculty and Senior Academic Leadership, 2007
    - The Spellings Commission, 2007
    - The View from the Helm, Leading the American University During an Era of Change, 2007
    - The View from the Helm, Leading the American University During an Era of Change (Illustrated), 2007
    - Raising the Bar: America's Challenge to Higher Education, 1/12/2007
    - Raising the Bar: America's Challenge to Higher Education (Spelling), 1/12/2007
    - The Future of the University: A Perspective from the Oort Cloud, 2007-02
    - The Michigan Mandate: Looking Back and Looking Forward, 2/14/2007
    - Celebrating the Past by Imaging the Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education, 4/14/2007
    - The Midwest Region and the Knowledge Economy - A Roadmap to the Future, 5/15/2007
    - The Midwest Region and the Knowledge Economy - A Roadmap to the Future (Midwest Media Project), 5/15/2007
    - Brookings Summary Remarks, 6/28/2007
    - Higher Education in the 21st Century: Global Imperatives, Regional Challenges, National Responsibilities, and Emerging Challenges, 9/1/2007
    - Higher Education in the 21st Century: Global Imperatives, Regional Challenges, National Responsibilities, and Emerging Opportunities, 9/1/2007
    - Critical Choices: Science, Energy, and Security, 2008
    - Engineering for a Changing World - A Roadmap to the Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education, 2008
    - Engineering for a Changing World - A Roadmap to the Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education (Flexner), 2008
    - Engineering for a Changing World - A Roadmap to the Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education - Grasso, 2008
    - Engineering for a Changing World - The Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education (ABET), 2008
    - Engineering for a Changing World - The Future of Engineering Practice, Research, and Education (Flexner), 2008
    - Higher Education, A Global Perspective, 2008
    - Hubs of Transformation: Leveraging the Great Lakes Research Complex for Energy Sector Innovation, 2008
    - The Michigan Roadmap Redux - A Call for Leadership, 2008
    - The Michigan Roadmap Redux, A Call for Leadership, 2008
    - A National Energy Research Network - A Step Toward America's Sustainability, 2008
    - A Proposed Study of the Changing Nature of the American Research University Ecosystem (1), 2008
    - A Proposed Study of the Changing Nature of the American Research University Ecosystem (2), 2008
    - Senate Assembly Address, 2008
    - UTEP Talk, 2008
    - The Vital Connection: Reclaiming Great Lakes Economic Leadership in the Bi-National US-Canadian Region, 2008-03
    - The Navigation of Universities Through a Flat World (EAU trimmed), 3/25/2008
    - The Navigation of Universities through a Flat World (EAU), 3/25/2008
    - The Navigation of Universities through a Flat World (Flexner), 3/25/2008
    - Aligning American Higher Education with a 21st-Century Public Agenda, 6/8/2008
    - Aligning American Higher Education with a 21st-Century Public Agenda, 6/8/2008